# Rodrigo Marquez

Software Developer



(702)581-5599



□ rodrigo.nmn.marquez@gmail.com



LinkedIn/rodrigo-marquez



GitHub/RodrigoM09

Highly adaptable and solution-focused professional with a strong background in military operations and experience in high-stress, fast-paced environments. Proven track record of quickly mastering new roles and technologies, resulting in positive outcomes and efficiency improvements. Strong communication skills and ability to work effectively in a team. Seeking opportunities to utilize my technical skills and experience in a challenging and dynamic technical role.

### Technical Skills

HTML - CSS - Bootstrap - JavaScript - jQuery - Java SE - Java EE (Servlets, JSP) - Spring - MySQL - Object-Oriented Programming - Test-Driven Development - Version Control with Git - Paired Programming

### **Development Projects**

Favorite Movies: <a href="https://github.com/rodrigo-tesfalem-movie-app/movi

As part of the Favorite Movies project, I developed a web application that allows users to create a personal list of their favorite movies. Users can add movies to their list by searching for them by title or by browsing through a list of popular movies. The application utilizes a database to store each user's movie list and allows them to view, add, and remove movies from their list. This project demonstrates my skills in web development, database management, and user experience design.

Weather Project: https://github.com/RodrigoM09/codeup-web-exercises/blob/main/html/weather map.html

I created a weather web application as part of a project at Codeup. The application allows users to search for the weather and view a map of any location they enter. It utilizes API calls to retrieve real-time weather data and map information. This project demonstrates my skills in API integration, web development, and user experience design.

Personal Website: https://github.com/RodrigoM09/my-stuff/tree/main/HTML

I developed a personal website to showcase my resume and professional experience. The website features interactive elements and is designed to be responsive and adapt to different screen sizes and devices. This project demonstrates my skills in web development, user experience design, and responsive design.

### Military Experience

**U.S Army** - United States

Squad Leader / Jan 2009 - Sep 2018

- Accountable for the welfare, fitness, morale, and discipline of 12 to 30 Soldiers
- Developed and delivered training programs in preparation for combat deployment
- Maintained accurate inventory for \$5 million of operating equipment including issuance and maintenance.
- Created and fostered an atmosphere of tolerance and free of harassment, developing a unified and team driven spirit.

U.S Army - Kabul, Afghanistan

Squad Leader / Apr 2011 - May 2012

- Responsible for security and safety of soldiers and equipment during missions.
- Maintained responsibility for supervising and operating wheeled vehicles and equipment on diverse terrain and roadways while providing critical support and advanced mobility to my team members
- Directed crews over 5,500 miles which includes over 200 movements between 14 Forward Operating Bases in Afghanistan
- Employed critical thinking to successfully and safely operate in the lead position on combat logistic patrols and advised convoy members of potential threats on the roadways

## **Professional Experience**

Sapphire Gentlemen's Club - Las Vegas, NV

VIP Guest Experience / Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

- Provided exceptional personalized service and ensured all guest needs were met in a prompt and efficient manner
- Worked with other departments to ensure a seamless and entertaining experience for our customers.

### **LifeTime Fitness** - Las Vegas, NV *Personal Trainer /* Aug 2018 - Aug 2020

- Developed safe, professional, and comprehensive client programs that drove client goal achievement and retention.
- Conducted fitness consultations for new clients including pre-participation screening, Medical History, Lifestyle questionnaire, and goal setting to assess and recommend personal training programs
- Ensured all members felt competent, confident, and connected by providing superior customer service through complementary and fee based services/programming
- Remained current on certifications and new trends in the industry.

### Education

#### Codeup

Certification of Completion

Aug 2022 - Feb 2023

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 20-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development.

#### **FitOps**

Certificate of Completion

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

8 week, fully-immersive Personal Training program. FitOps provides education for veterans by top fitness and health industry professionals. Program is accelerated and designed to jumpstart a career in the fitness industry.